# **Kevin Beesley**

Web engineer solving problems in the entire stack.

Lawrence, KS 66049 (918) 671-0408 kbeesley.dev@gmail.com

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

I have grown from a new CS graduate programming on custom ruggedized handheld computers for propane delivery systems to leading developers and teams creating web application systems for a global nonprofit society. I have gained valuable experience from end user software/hardware support to software system architecture design and implementation. I will continue to guide organizations in their web application strategies and architectures and solve their major business pains in alignment with their mission.

#### **CAREER DETAILS**

## Society of Exploration Geophysicists, Tulsa OK

Technical Lead Jul 2013 - Present

Programmer/Analyst Feb 2004 - Jul 2013

SEG is The international society of applied geophysics providing technical magazines, online digital reference library, technical conferences and lectures, publishing, an online store, and various other services to its global 25K+ members. My career at SEG started as a programmer maintaining and rewriting legacy systems, to a Technical Lead guiding the development team implementing new CRM-integrated systems.

- I was brought over from my former employer (TouchStar Technologies) by the SEG director of IT Art Schrader (former manager at TouchStar). Art knew first-hand my abilities, that I was a great developer, and was a perfect fit for the culture he wanted.
- SEG had an in-house registration system that was only used for its Annual Meeting every year but needed a system that could be used for multiple simultaneous conferences. I led the team of developers in the creation of a new conference registration system integrating it into our CRM system allowing for multi-year multi-conference attendee and member registrations to be tracked and reported in one place saving costs in annual maintenance, time, and allowed more online registrations and shorter onsite registration lines at the conferences.
- When a previous attempt at out-sourcing our online presence design and implementation failed, I was the biggest proponent of using free open-source technologies to replace the burdensome contractor provided website. We used an open-source portal on existing hardware and over the course of a year brought to life a new website and site design that saved SEG \$248K per year in maintenance costs.

### **TECHNOLOGIES**

HTML/CSS

Javascript

**jQuery** 

Angular

Express

.Net (ASP.Net, C#, VB.Net)

Java

Coldfusion

PHP

Mongo

MS SQL Server

MySQL

Agile/SCRUM

Jira

Confluence

Bamboo

Fisheye

## TouchStar Technologies, Tulsa OK

Programmer Aug 1999 - Feb 2004

TouchStar develops software solutions mainly for the energy delivery sector, but also any market where a ruggedized solution is needed. I was hired fresh out of college to develop propane delivery and invoicing software on a ruggedized handheld device. Developing for a ruggedized handheld device made me learn the value of efficient code, attention to memory details, and most importantly the value of screen real estate and the importance of layout.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Tulsa, Tulsa OK

B.S. Computer Science Aug 1995 - May 1999

## **CURRENT PROJECTS**

## **RSVP web application** — *TPSi*, *Tulsa OK*

TPSi has a lot of manual work managing the invitations for their customer Christmas party every year – the previous system required a lot of setup each year, manual upkeep, and importing of customers from various spreadsheets. My partner and I are creating a public RSVP page for customers as well as an administrative interface to input new events, manage customers, and manage staff making new events easier to manage.

Kevin Beesley 2 of 2